<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>University of Trieste on RL4AA Collaboration | Homepage</title><link>https://RL4aa.github.io/tags/university-of-trieste/</link><description>Recent content in University of Trieste on RL4AA Collaboration | Homepage</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://RL4aa.github.io/tags/university-of-trieste/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Feasibility Investigation on Several Reinforcement Learning Techniques to Improve the Performance of the FERMI Free-Electron Laser</title><link>https://RL4aa.github.io/posts/publications/bruchon2021feasiblity/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://RL4aa.github.io/posts/publications/bruchon2021feasiblity/</guid><description>N. Bruchon
University of Trieste
PhD thesis
Abstract The research carried out in particle accelerator facilities does not concern only particle and condensed matter physics, although these are the main topics covered in the field. Indeed, since a particle accelerator is composed of many different sub-systems, its proper functioning depends both on each of these parts and their interconnection. It follows that the study, implementation, and improvement of the various sub-systems are fundamental points of investigation too.</description></item><item><title>Policy gradient methods for free-electron laser and terahertz source optimization and stabilization at the FERMI free-electron laser at Elettra</title><link>https://RL4aa.github.io/posts/publications/oshea202policy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://RL4aa.github.io/posts/publications/oshea202policy/</guid><description>F. H. O&amp;rsquo;Shea1, N. Bruchon2, G. Gaio1
1Elettra Sincrotrone Trieste, 2University of Trieste
Physical Review Accelerators and Beams
Abstract In this article we report on the application of a model-free reinforcement learning method to the optimization of accelerator systems. We simplify a policy gradient algorithm to accelerator control from sophisticated algorithms that have recently been demonstrated to solve complex dynamic problems. After outlining a theoretical basis for the functioning of the algorithm, we explore the small hyperparameter space to develop intuition about said parameters using a simple number-guess environment.</description></item><item><title>Model-free and Bayesian Ensembling Model-based Deep Reinforcement Learning for Particle Accelerator Control Demonstrated on the FERMI FEL</title><link>https://RL4aa.github.io/posts/publications/hirlaender2020modelfree/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://RL4aa.github.io/posts/publications/hirlaender2020modelfree/</guid><description>S. Hirlaender1, N. Bruchon2
1University of Salzburg, 2University of Trieste
arXiv
Abstract Reinforcement learning holds tremendous promise in accelerator controls. The primary goal of this paper is to show how this approach can be utilised on an operational level on accelerator physics problems. Despite the success of model-free reinforcement learning in several domains, sample-efficiency still is a bottle-neck, which might be encompassed by model-based methods. We compare well-suited purely model-based to model-free reinforcement learning applied to the intensity optimisation on the FERMI FEL system.</description></item><item><title>Sample-efficient reinforcement learning for CERN accelerator control</title><link>https://RL4aa.github.io/posts/publications/kain2020sampleefficient/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://RL4aa.github.io/posts/publications/kain2020sampleefficient/</guid><description>V. Kain1, S. Hirlander1, B. Goddard1, F. M. Velotti1, G. Z. Della Porta1, N. Bruchon2, G. Valentino3
1CERN, 2University of Trieste, 3University of Malta
Physical Review Accelerators and Beams
Abstract Numerical optimization algorithms are already established tools to increase and stabilize the performance of particle accelerators. These algorithms have many advantages, are available out of the box, and can be adapted to a wide range of optimization problems in accelerator operation.</description></item><item><title>Basic Reinforcement Learning Techniques to Control the Intensity of a Seeded Free-Electron Laser</title><link>https://RL4aa.github.io/posts/publications/bruchon2020basic/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://RL4aa.github.io/posts/publications/bruchon2020basic/</guid><description>N. Bruchon1, G. Fenu1, G. Gaio2, M. Lonza2, F. H. O’Shea2, F. A. Pellegrino1, E. Salvato1
1University of Trieste, 2Elettra Sincrotrone Trieste
Electronics
Abstract Optimal tuning of particle accelerators is a challenging task. Many different approaches have been proposed in the past to solve two main problems—attainment of an optimal working point and performance recovery after machine drifts. The most classical model-free techniques (e.g., Gradient Ascent or Extremum Seeking algorithms) have some intrinsic limitations.</description></item><item><title>Toward the Application of Reinforcement Learning to the Intensity Control of a Seeded Free-Electron Laser</title><link>https://RL4aa.github.io/posts/publications/bruchon2019toward/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://RL4aa.github.io/posts/publications/bruchon2019toward/</guid><description>N. Bruchon, G. Fenu, G. Gaio, M. Lonza, F. A. Pellegrino, E. Salvato
University of Trieste
23rd International Conference on Mechatronics Technology
Abstract The optimization of particle accelerators is a challenging task, and many different approaches have been proposed in years, to obtain an optimal tuning of the plant and to keep it optimally tuned despite drifts or disturbances. Indeed, the classical model-free approaches (such as Gradient Ascent or Extremum Seeking algorithms) have intrinsic limitations.</description></item><item><title>Free-electron Laser Optimization with Reinforcement Learning</title><link>https://RL4aa.github.io/posts/publications/bruchon2019freeelectron/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://RL4aa.github.io/posts/publications/bruchon2019freeelectron/</guid><description>N. Bruchon1, G. Gaio2, G. Fenu1, M. Lonza2, F. A. Pellegrino1, E. Salvato1
1University of Trieste, 2Elettra Sincrotrone Trieste
17th International Conference on Accelerator and Large Experimental Physics Control Systems
Abstract Reinforcement Learning (RL) is one of the most promis-ing techniques in Machine Learning because of its modestcomputational requirements with respect to other algorithms.RL uses an agent that takes actions within its environmentto maximize a reward related to the goal it is designed toachieve.</description></item></channel></rss>