<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>kara on &lt;img src="imgs/rl4aa_logo.png"/> RL4AA Collaboration | Homepage</title><link>https://RL4aa.github.io/tags/kara/</link><description>Recent content in kara on &lt;img src="imgs/rl4aa_logo.png"/> RL4AA Collaboration | Homepage</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://RL4aa.github.io/tags/kara/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Micro-Bunching Control at Electron Storage Rings with Reinforcement Learning</title><link>https://RL4aa.github.io/posts/publications/boltz2019microbunching/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://RL4aa.github.io/posts/publications/boltz2019microbunching/</guid><description>T. Boltz
Karlsruhe Insitute of Technology KIT
PhD thesis
Abstract At the time this thesis is written, the world finds itself amidst and partly in the process of recovering from the COVID-19 pandemic caused by the SARS-Cov-2 virus. One major contribution to the worldwide efforts of bringing this pandemic to an end are the vaccines developed by different research teams all around the globe. Produced in a remarkably short time frame, a crucial first step for the discovery of these vaccines was mapping out the atomic structure of the proteins making up the virus and their interactions.</description></item><item><title>Accelerated Deep Reinforcement Learning for Fast Feedback of Beam Dynamics at KARA</title><link>https://RL4aa.github.io/posts/publications/wang2021accelerated/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://RL4aa.github.io/posts/publications/wang2021accelerated/</guid><description>W. Wang1, M. Caselle1, T. Boltz1, E. Blomley1, M. Brosi1, T. Dritschler1, A. Ebersoldt1, A. Kopmann1, A. Santamaria Garcia1, P. Schreiber1, E. Br端ndermann1, M. Weber1, A.-S. M端ller1, Y. Fang2
1Karlsruhe Insitute of Technology KIT, 2Northwestern Polytechnical University
IEEE Transactions on Nuclear Science
Abstract Coherent synchrotron radiation (CSR) is generated when the electron bunch length is in the order of the magnitude of the wavelength of the emitted radiation. The self-interaction of short electron bunches with their own electromagnetic fields changes the longitudinal beam dynamics significantly.</description></item><item><title>Feedback Design for Control of the Micro-Bunching Instability Based on Reinforcement Learning</title><link>https://RL4aa.github.io/posts/publications/boltz2019feedback/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://RL4aa.github.io/posts/publications/boltz2019feedback/</guid><description>T. Boltz, M. Brosi, E. Br端ndermann, B. Haerer, P. Kaiser, C. Pohl, P. Schreiber, M. Yan,T. Asfour, A.-S. M端ller
Karlsruhe Insitute of Technology KIT
10th International Particle Accelerator Conference
Abstract The operation of ring-based synchrotron light sourceswith short electron bunches increases the emission of co-herent synchrotron radiation (CSR) in the THz frequencyrange. However, the micro-bunching instability resultingfrom self-interaction of the bunch with its own radiationfield limits stable operation with constant intensity of CSRemission to a particular threshold current.</description></item></channel></rss>