<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>linac4 on RL4AA Collaboration | Homepage</title><link>https://RL4aa.github.io/tags/linac4/</link><description>Recent content in linac4 on RL4AA Collaboration | Homepage</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://RL4aa.github.io/tags/linac4/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Test of Machine Learning at the CERN LINAC4</title><link>https://RL4aa.github.io/posts/publications/kain2021test/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://RL4aa.github.io/posts/publications/kain2021test/</guid><description>V. Kain1, N. Bruchon1, S. Hirlander1, N. Madysa1, I. Vojskovic1, P. Skowronski1, G. Valentino2
1CERN, 2University of Malta
61st ICFA ABDW on High-Intensity and High-Brightness Hadron Beams
Abstract The CERN H−linear accelerator, LINAC4, served as atest bed for advanced algorithms during the CERN LongShutdown 2 in the years 2019/20. One of the main goals wasto show that reinforcement learning with all its benefits canbe used as a replacement for numerical optimization and asa complement to classical control in the accelerator controlcontext.</description></item><item><title>Sample-efficient reinforcement learning for CERN accelerator control</title><link>https://RL4aa.github.io/posts/publications/kain2020sampleefficient/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://RL4aa.github.io/posts/publications/kain2020sampleefficient/</guid><description>V. Kain1, S. Hirlander1, B. Goddard1, F. M. Velotti1, G. Z. Della Porta1, N. Bruchon2, G. Valentino3
1CERN, 2University of Trieste, 3University of Malta
Physical Review Accelerators and Beams
Abstract Numerical optimization algorithms are already established tools to increase and stabilize the performance of particle accelerators. These algorithms have many advantages, are available out of the box, and can be adapted to a wide range of optimization problems in accelerator operation.</description></item></channel></rss>