<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>fermi fel on RL4AA Collaboration | Homepage</title><link>https://RL4aa.github.io/tags/fermi-fel/</link><description>Recent content in fermi fel on RL4AA Collaboration | Homepage</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://RL4aa.github.io/tags/fermi-fel/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Policy gradient methods for free-electron laser and terahertz source optimization and stabilization at the FERMI free-electron laser at Elettra</title><link>https://RL4aa.github.io/posts/publications/oshea202policy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://RL4aa.github.io/posts/publications/oshea202policy/</guid><description>F. H. O&amp;rsquo;Shea1, N. Bruchon2, G. Gaio1
1Elettra Sincrotrone Trieste, 2University of Trieste
Physical Review Accelerators and Beams
Abstract In this article we report on the application of a model-free reinforcement learning method to the optimization of accelerator systems. We simplify a policy gradient algorithm to accelerator control from sophisticated algorithms that have recently been demonstrated to solve complex dynamic problems. After outlining a theoretical basis for the functioning of the algorithm, we explore the small hyperparameter space to develop intuition about said parameters using a simple number-guess environment.</description></item><item><title>Model-free and Bayesian Ensembling Model-based Deep Reinforcement Learning for Particle Accelerator Control Demonstrated on the FERMI FEL</title><link>https://RL4aa.github.io/posts/publications/hirlaender2020modelfree/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://RL4aa.github.io/posts/publications/hirlaender2020modelfree/</guid><description>S. Hirlaender1, N. Bruchon2
1University of Salzburg, 2University of Trieste
arXiv
Abstract Reinforcement learning holds tremendous promise in accelerator controls. The primary goal of this paper is to show how this approach can be utilised on an operational level on accelerator physics problems. Despite the success of model-free reinforcement learning in several domains, sample-efficiency still is a bottle-neck, which might be encompassed by model-based methods. We compare well-suited purely model-based to model-free reinforcement learning applied to the intensity optimisation on the FERMI FEL system.</description></item><item><title>Basic Reinforcement Learning Techniques to Control the Intensity of a Seeded Free-Electron Laser</title><link>https://RL4aa.github.io/posts/publications/bruchon2020basic/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://RL4aa.github.io/posts/publications/bruchon2020basic/</guid><description>N. Bruchon1, G. Fenu1, G. Gaio2, M. Lonza2, F. H. O’Shea2, F. A. Pellegrino1, E. Salvato1
1University of Trieste, 2Elettra Sincrotrone Trieste
Electronics
Abstract Optimal tuning of particle accelerators is a challenging task. Many different approaches have been proposed in the past to solve two main problems—attainment of an optimal working point and performance recovery after machine drifts. The most classical model-free techniques (e.g., Gradient Ascent or Extremum Seeking algorithms) have some intrinsic limitations.</description></item></channel></rss>