<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Icalepcs on RL4AA Collaboration | Homepage</title><link>https://RL4aa.github.io/tags/icalepcs/</link><description>Recent content in Icalepcs on RL4AA Collaboration | Homepage</description><generator>Hugo -- 0.152.1</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://RL4aa.github.io/tags/icalepcs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Free-electron Laser Optimization with Reinforcement Learning</title><link>https://RL4aa.github.io/posts/publications/bruchon2019freeelectron/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://RL4aa.github.io/posts/publications/bruchon2019freeelectron/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;N. Bruchon&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;, G. Gaio&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;, G. Fenu&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;, M. Lonza&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;, F. A. Pellegrino&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;, E. Salvato&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;University of Trieste, &lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;Elettra Sincrotrone Trieste&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;17th International Conference on Accelerator and Large Experimental Physics Control Systems&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="abstract"&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reinforcement Learning (RL) is one of the most promis-ing techniques in Machine Learning because of its modestcomputational requirements with respect to other algorithms.RL uses an agent that takes actions within its environmentto maximize a reward related to the goal it is designed toachieve. We have recently used RL as a model-free approachto improve the performance of the FERMI Free ElectronLaser. A number of machine parameters are adjusted tofind the optimum FEL output in terms of intensity and spec-tral quality. In particular we focus on the problem of thealignment of the seed laser with the electron beam, initiallyusing a simplified model and then applying the developedalgorithm on the real machine. This paper reports the resultsobtained and discusses pros and cons of this approach withplans for future applications.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>