<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>kit on RL4AA Collaboration | Homepage</title><link>https://RL4aa.github.io/tags/kit/</link><description>Recent content in kit on RL4AA Collaboration | Homepage</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://RL4aa.github.io/tags/kit/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>RL4AA'23: 1st Collaboration Workshop on Reinforcement Learning for Autonomous Accelerators</title><link>https://RL4aa.github.io/posts/announcements/rl4aa23/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://RL4aa.github.io/posts/announcements/rl4aa23/</guid><description>Reinforcement learning is the most difficult learning paradigms to understand and to efficiently use, but it holds a lot of promise in the field of accelerator physics. The applications of reinforcement learning to accelerators today are not very numerous yet, but the interest of the community is growing considerably. This is how the 1st collaboration workshop on Reinforcement Learning for Autonomous Accelerators (RL4AA'23) came to be! The AI4Accelerators team organized and hosted the workshop at KIT, gathering colleagues involved in reinforcement learning.</description></item><item><title>Feedback Design for Control of the Micro-Bunching Instability Based on Reinforcement Learning</title><link>https://RL4aa.github.io/posts/publications/boltz2019feedback/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://RL4aa.github.io/posts/publications/boltz2019feedback/</guid><description>T. Boltz, M. Brosi, E. Bründermann, B. Haerer, P. Kaiser, C. Pohl, P. Schreiber, M. Yan,T. Asfour, A.-S. Müller. Karlsruhe Insitute of Technology KIT. 10th International Particle Accelerator Conference.
Abstract The operation of ring-based synchrotron light sourceswith short electron bunches increases the emission of co-herent synchrotron radiation (CSR) in the THz frequencyrange. However, the micro-bunching instability resultingfrom self-interaction of the bunch with its own radiationfield limits stable operation with constant intensity of CSRemission to a particular threshold current.</description></item></channel></rss>