<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>kit on RL4AA Collaboration | Homepage</title><link>https://RL4aa.github.io/tags/kit/</link><description>Recent content in kit on RL4AA Collaboration | Homepage</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://RL4aa.github.io/tags/kit/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Learning to Do or Learning While Doing: Reinforcement Learning and Bayesian Optimisation for Online Continuous Tuning</title><link>https://RL4aa.github.io/posts/publications/kaiser2023learning/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://RL4aa.github.io/posts/publications/kaiser2023learning/</guid><description>J. Kaiser1, C. Xu2, A. Eichler1, A. Santamaria Garcia2, O. Stein1, E. Bründermann2, W. Kuropka1, H. Dinter1, F. Mayet1, T. Vinatier1, F. Burkart1, H. Schlarb1
1Deutsches Elektronen-Synchrotron DESY, 2 Karlsruhe Institute of Technology KIT
arXiv
Abstract Online tuning of real-world plants is a complex optimisation problem that continues to require manual intervention by experienced human operators. Autonomous tuning is a rapidly expanding field of research, where learning-based methods, such as Reinforcement Learning-trained Optimisation (RLO) and Bayesian optimisation (BO), hold great promise for achieving outstanding plant performance and reducing tuning times.</description></item><item><title>RL4AA'23: 1st Collaboration Workshop on Reinforcement Learning for Autonomous Accelerators</title><link>https://RL4aa.github.io/posts/announcements/rl4aa23/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://RL4aa.github.io/posts/announcements/rl4aa23/</guid><description>Reinforcement learning is the most difficult learning paradigms to understand and to efficiently use, but it holds a lot of promise in the field of accelerator physics. The applications of reinforcement learning to accelerators today are not very numerous yet, but the interest of the community is growing considerably. This is how the 1st collaboration workshop on Reinforcement Learning for Autonomous Accelerators (RL4AA'23) came to be! The AI4Accelerators team organized and hosted the workshop at KIT, gathering colleagues involved in reinforcement learning.</description></item><item><title>Micro-Bunching Control at Electron Storage Rings with Reinforcement Learning</title><link>https://RL4aa.github.io/posts/publications/boltz2019microbunching/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://RL4aa.github.io/posts/publications/boltz2019microbunching/</guid><description>T. Boltz
Karlsruhe Insitute of Technology KIT
PhD thesis
Abstract At the time this thesis is written, the world finds itself amidst and partly in the process of recovering from the COVID-19 pandemic caused by the SARS-Cov-2 virus. One major contribution to the worldwide efforts of bringing this pandemic to an end are the vaccines developed by different research teams all around the globe. Produced in a remarkably short time frame, a crucial first step for the discovery of these vaccines was mapping out the atomic structure of the proteins making up the virus and their interactions.</description></item><item><title>Accelerated Deep Reinforcement Learning for Fast Feedback of Beam Dynamics at KARA</title><link>https://RL4aa.github.io/posts/publications/wang2021accelerated/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://RL4aa.github.io/posts/publications/wang2021accelerated/</guid><description>W. Wang1, M. Caselle1, T. Boltz1, E. Blomley1, M. Brosi1, T. Dritschler1, A. Ebersoldt1, A. Kopmann1, A. Santamaria Garcia1, P. Schreiber1, E. Bründermann1, M. Weber1, A.-S. Müller1, Y. Fang2
1Karlsruhe Insitute of Technology KIT, 2Northwestern Polytechnical University
IEEE Transactions on Nuclear Science
Abstract Coherent synchrotron radiation (CSR) is generated when the electron bunch length is in the order of the magnitude of the wavelength of the emitted radiation. The self-interaction of short electron bunches with their own electromagnetic fields changes the longitudinal beam dynamics significantly.</description></item><item><title>First Steps Toward an Autonomous Accelerator, A Common Project Between DESY and KIT</title><link>https://RL4aa.github.io/posts/publications/eichler2021first/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://RL4aa.github.io/posts/publications/eichler2021first/</guid><description>A. Eichler1, F. Burkart1, J. Kaiser1, W. Kuropka1, O. Stein1, E. Bründermann2, A. Santamaria Garcia2, C. Xu2
1Deutsches Elektronen-Synchrotron DESY, 2Karlsruhe Institute of Technology KIT
12th International Particle Accelerator Conference
Abstract Reinforcement learning algorithms have risen in pop-ularity in the accelerator physics community in recentyears, showing potential in beam control and in the opti-mization and automation of tasks in accelerator operation.The Helmholtz AI project “Machine Learning Toward Au-tonomous Accelerators” is a collaboration between DESYand KIT that works on investigating and developing rein-forcement learning applications for the automatic start-upof electron linear accelerators.</description></item><item><title>Feedback Design for Control of the Micro-Bunching Instability Based on Reinforcement Learning</title><link>https://RL4aa.github.io/posts/publications/boltz2019feedback/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://RL4aa.github.io/posts/publications/boltz2019feedback/</guid><description>T. Boltz, M. Brosi, E. Bründermann, B. Haerer, P. Kaiser, C. Pohl, P. Schreiber, M. Yan,T. Asfour, A.-S. Müller
Karlsruhe Insitute of Technology KIT
10th International Particle Accelerator Conference
Abstract The operation of ring-based synchrotron light sourceswith short electron bunches increases the emission of co-herent synchrotron radiation (CSR) in the THz frequencyrange. However, the micro-bunching instability resultingfrom self-interaction of the bunch with its own radiationfield limits stable operation with constant intensity of CSRemission to a particular threshold current.</description></item></channel></rss>