<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>journal article on RL4AA Collaboration | Homepage</title><link>https://RL4aa.github.io/tags/journal-article/</link><description>Recent content in journal article on RL4AA Collaboration | Homepage</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://RL4aa.github.io/tags/journal-article/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Sample-efficient reinforcement learning for CERN accelerator control</title><link>https://RL4aa.github.io/posts/kain2020sampleefficient/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://RL4aa.github.io/posts/kain2020sampleefficient/</guid><description>V. Kain, S. Hirlander, B. Goddard, F. M. Velotti, G. Z. Della Porta, N. Bruchon, G. Valentino. CERN, University of Trieste, University of Malta. Physical Review Accelerators and Beams.
Abstract Numerical optimization algorithms are already established tools to increase and stabilize the performance of particle accelerators. These algorithms have many advantages, are available out of the box, and can be adapted to a wide range of optimization problems in accelerator operation.</description></item><item><title>Basic Reinforcement Learning Techniques to Control the Intensity of a Seeded Free-Electron Laser</title><link>https://RL4aa.github.io/posts/bruchon2020basic/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://RL4aa.github.io/posts/bruchon2020basic/</guid><description>N. Bruchon, G. Fenu, G. Gaio, M. Lonza, F. H. O’Shea, F. A. Pellegrino, E. Salvato. University of Trieste, Elettra Sincrotrone Trieste. Electronics.
Abstract Optimal tuning of particle accelerators is a challenging task. Many different approaches have been proposed in the past to solve two main problems—attainment of an optimal working point and performance recovery after machine drifts. The most classical model-free techniques (e.g., Gradient Ascent or Extremum Seeking algorithms) have some intrinsic limitations.</description></item></channel></rss>