<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>University of Salzburg on &lt;img src="imgs/rl4aa_logo.png"/> RL4AA Collaboration | Homepage</title><link>https://RL4aa.github.io/tags/university-of-salzburg/</link><description>Recent content in University of Salzburg on &lt;img src="imgs/rl4aa_logo.png"/> RL4AA Collaboration | Homepage</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://RL4aa.github.io/tags/university-of-salzburg/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Towards automatic setup of 18 MeV electron beamline using machine learning</title><link>https://RL4aa.github.io/posts/publications/velotti2023towards/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://RL4aa.github.io/posts/publications/velotti2023towards/</guid><description>F. M. Velotti1, B. Goddard1, V. Kain1, R. Ramjiawan1, G. Z. Della Porta1 and S. Hirlaender2
1CERN, 2University of Salzburg
Machine Learning: Science and Technology
Abstract To improve the performance-critical stability and brightness of the electron bunch at injection into the proton-driven plasma wakefield at the AWAKE CERN experiment, automation approaches based on unsupervised machine learning (ML) were developed and deployed. Numerical optimisers were tested together with different model-free reinforcement learning (RL) agents.</description></item><item><title>Application of reinforcement learning in the LHC tune feedback</title><link>https://RL4aa.github.io/posts/publications/grech2022application/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://RL4aa.github.io/posts/publications/grech2022application/</guid><description>L. Grech1, G. Valentino1, D. Alves2 and Simon Hirlaender3
1University of Malta, 2CERN, 3University of Salzburg
Frontiers in Physics
Abstract The Beam-Based Feedback System (BBFS) was primarily responsible for correcting the beam energy, orbit and tune in the CERN Large Hadron Collider (LHC). A major code renovation of the BBFS was planned and carried out during the LHC Long Shutdown 2 (LS2). This work consists of an explorative study to solve a beam-based control problem, the tune feedback (QFB), utilising state-of-the-art Reinforcement Learning (RL).</description></item><item><title>Model-free and Bayesian Ensembling Model-based Deep Reinforcement Learning for Particle Accelerator Control Demonstrated on the FERMI FEL</title><link>https://RL4aa.github.io/posts/publications/hirlaender2020modelfree/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://RL4aa.github.io/posts/publications/hirlaender2020modelfree/</guid><description>S. Hirlaender1, N. Bruchon2
1University of Salzburg, 2University of Trieste
arXiv
Abstract Reinforcement learning holds tremendous promise in accelerator controls. The primary goal of this paper is to show how this approach can be utilised on an operational level on accelerator physics problems. Despite the success of model-free reinforcement learning in several domains, sample-efficiency still is a bottle-neck, which might be encompassed by model-based methods. We compare well-suited purely model-based to model-free reinforcement learning applied to the intensity optimisation on the FERMI FEL system.</description></item></channel></rss>