<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>ipac on RL4AA Collaboration | Homepage</title><link>https://RL4aa.github.io/tags/ipac/</link><description>Recent content in ipac on RL4AA Collaboration | Homepage</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://RL4aa.github.io/tags/ipac/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Ultra fast reinforcement learning demonstrated at CERN AWAKE</title><link>https://RL4aa.github.io/posts/publications/ultra_fast_rl_awake/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://RL4aa.github.io/posts/publications/ultra_fast_rl_awake/</guid><description>** Simon Hirlaender, Lukas Lamminger, Giovanni Zevi Della Porta, Verena Kain**
Abstract Reinforcement learning (RL) is a promising direction in machine learning for the control and optimisation of particle accelerators since it learns directly from experience without needing a model a-priori. However, RL generally suffers from low sample efficiency and thus training from scracth on the machine is often not an option. RL agents are usually trained or pre-tuned on simulators and then transferred to the real environment.</description></item><item><title>Automated Intensity Optimisation Using Reinforcement Learning at LEIR</title><link>https://RL4aa.github.io/posts/publications/madysa2022automated/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://RL4aa.github.io/posts/publications/madysa2022automated/</guid><description>N. Madysa, V. Kain, R. Alemany Fernandez, N. Biancacci, B. Goddard, F. M. Velotti
CERN
13th Particle Accelerator Conference
Abstract High intensities in the Low Energy Ion Ring (LEIR) at CERN are achieved by stacking several multi-turn injec- tions from the pre-accelerator Linac3. Up to seven consec- utive 200 μs long, 200 ms spaced pulses are injected from Linac3 into LEIR. Two inclined septa, one magnetic and one electrostatic, combined with a collapsing horizontal or- bit bump allows a 6-D phase space painting via a linearly ramped mean momentum along the Linac3 pulse and in- jection at high dispersion.</description></item><item><title>First Steps Toward an Autonomous Accelerator, A Common Project Between DESY and KIT</title><link>https://RL4aa.github.io/posts/publications/eichler2021first/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://RL4aa.github.io/posts/publications/eichler2021first/</guid><description>A. Eichler1, F. Burkart1, J. Kaiser1, W. Kuropka1, O. Stein1, E. Bründermann2, A. Santamaria Garcia2, C. Xu2
1Deutsches Elektronen-Synchrotron DESY, 2Karlsruhe Institute of Technology KIT
12th International Particle Accelerator Conference
Abstract Reinforcement learning algorithms have risen in pop-ularity in the accelerator physics community in recentyears, showing potential in beam control and in the opti-mization and automation of tasks in accelerator operation.The Helmholtz AI project “Machine Learning Toward Au-tonomous Accelerators” is a collaboration between DESYand KIT that works on investigating and developing rein-forcement learning applications for the automatic start-upof electron linear accelerators.</description></item><item><title>Physics-Enhanced Reinforcement Learning for Optimal Control</title><link>https://RL4aa.github.io/posts/publications/ivanov2021physicsenhanced/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://RL4aa.github.io/posts/publications/ivanov2021physicsenhanced/</guid><description>A. Ivanov, I. Agapov, A. Eichler, S. Tomin
Deutsches Elektronen Synchrotron DESY
12th International Particle Accelerator Conference
Abstract We propose an approach for incorporating acceleratorphysics models into reinforcement learning agents. The proposed approach is based on the Taylor mapping technique for the simulation of particle dynamics. The resulting computational graph is represented as a polynomial neural network and embedded into the traditional reinforcement learning agents. The application of the model is demonstrated in a nonlinear simulation model of beam transmission.</description></item><item><title>Feedback Design for Control of the Micro-Bunching Instability Based on Reinforcement Learning</title><link>https://RL4aa.github.io/posts/publications/boltz2019feedback/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://RL4aa.github.io/posts/publications/boltz2019feedback/</guid><description>T. Boltz, M. Brosi, E. Bründermann, B. Haerer, P. Kaiser, C. Pohl, P. Schreiber, M. Yan,T. Asfour, A.-S. Müller
Karlsruhe Insitute of Technology KIT
10th International Particle Accelerator Conference
Abstract The operation of ring-based synchrotron light sourceswith short electron bunches increases the emission of co-herent synchrotron radiation (CSR) in the THz frequencyrange. However, the micro-bunching instability resultingfrom self-interaction of the bunch with its own radiationfield limits stable operation with constant intensity of CSRemission to a particular threshold current.</description></item><item><title>Orbit Correction Studies Using Neural Networks</title><link>https://RL4aa.github.io/posts/publications/meier2012orbit/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://RL4aa.github.io/posts/publications/meier2012orbit/</guid><description>E. Meier, Y.-R. E. Tan, G. S. LeBlanc
Australian Synchrotron
3rd International Particle Accelerator Conference
Abstract This paper reports the use of neural networks for orbitcorrection at the Australian Synchrotron Storage Ring. Theproposed system uses two neural networks in an actor-criticscheme to model a long term cost function and computeappropriate corrections. The system is entirely based onthe history of the beam position and the actuators, i.e. thecorrector magnets, in the storage ring.</description></item></channel></rss>