<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Publications on RL4AA Collaboration | Homepage</title><link>https://RL4aa.github.io/categories/publications/</link><description>Recent content in Publications on RL4AA Collaboration | Homepage</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://RL4aa.github.io/categories/publications/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Learning-based Optimisation of Particle Accelerators Under Partial Observability Without Real-World Training</title><link>https://RL4aa.github.io/posts/kaiser2022learningbased/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://RL4aa.github.io/posts/kaiser2022learningbased/</guid><description>Jan Kaiser, Oliver Stein, Annika Eichler. Deutsches Elektronen-Synchrotron DESY. 39th International Conference on Machine Learning.
Abstract In recent work, it has been shown that reinforcement learning (RL) is capable of solving a variety of problems at sometimes super-human performance levels. But despite continued advances in the field, applying RL to complex real-world control and optimisation problems has proven difficult. In this contribution, we demonstrate how to successfully apply RL to the optimisation of a highly complex real-world machine – specifically a linear particle accelerator – in an only partially observable setting and without requiring training on the real machine.</description></item><item><title>Feasibility Investigation on Several Reinforcement Learning Techniques to Improve the Performance of the FERMI Free-Electron Laser</title><link>https://RL4aa.github.io/posts/bruchon2021feasiblity/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://RL4aa.github.io/posts/bruchon2021feasiblity/</guid><description>Niky Bruchon. University of Trieste. PhD thesis.
Abstract The research carried out in particle accelerator facilities does not concern only particle and condensed matter physics, although these are the main topics covered in the field. Indeed, since a particle accelerator is composed of many different sub-systems, its proper functioning depends both on each of these parts and their interconnection. It follows that the study, implementation, and improvement of the various sub-systems are fundamental points of investigation too.</description></item></channel></rss>