<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Fermilab on RL4AA Collaboration | Homepage</title><link>https://RL4aa.github.io/tags/fermilab/</link><description>Recent content in Fermilab on RL4AA Collaboration | Homepage</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://RL4aa.github.io/tags/fermilab/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Real-time artificial intelligence for accelerator control: A study at the Fermilab Booster</title><link>https://RL4aa.github.io/posts/publications/stjohn2021realtime/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://RL4aa.github.io/posts/publications/stjohn2021realtime/</guid><description>J. St. John1, C. Herwig1, D. Kafkes1, J. Mitrevski1, W. A. Pellico1, G. N. Perdue1, A. Quintero-Parra1, B. A. Schupbach1, K. Seiya1, N. Tran1, M. Schram2, J. M. Duarte3, Y. Huang4, R. Keller5
1Fermi National Accelerator Laboratory, 2Thomas Jefferson National Accelerator Laboratory, 3University of California San Diego, 4Pacific Northwest National Laboratory, 5Columbia University
Physical Review Accelerators and Beams
Abstract We describe a method for precisely regulating the gradient magnet power supply (GMPS) at the Fermilab Booster accelerator complex using a neural network trained via reinforcement learning.</description></item><item><title>Neural Networks for Modeling and Control of Particle Accelerators</title><link>https://RL4aa.github.io/posts/publications/edelen2020neural/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://RL4aa.github.io/posts/publications/edelen2020neural/</guid><description>A. L. Edelen
Colorado State University
PhD thesis
Abstract Charged particle accelerators support a wide variety of scientific, industrial, and medical applications. They range in scale and complexity from systems with just a few components for beam acceleration and manipulation, to large scientific user facilities that span many kilometers and have hundreds-to-thousands of individually-controllable components. Specific operational requirements must be met by adjusting the many controllable variables of the accelerator. Meeting these requirements can be challenging, both in terms of the ability to achieve specific beam quality metrics in a reliable fashion and in terms of the time needed to set up and maintain the optimal operating conditions.</description></item><item><title>Using a neural network control policy for rapid switching between beam parameters in an FEL</title><link>https://RL4aa.github.io/posts/publications/edelen2017using/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://RL4aa.github.io/posts/publications/edelen2017using/</guid><description>A. L. Edelen1, S. G. Biedron2, J. P. Edelen3, S. V. Milton4, P. J. M. van der Slot5
1Colorado State University, 2Element Aero, 3Fermi National Accelerator Laboratory, 4Los Alamos National Laboratory, 5University of Twente
38th International Free Electron Laser Conference
Abstract FEL user facilities often must accommodate requests for a variety of beam parameters. This usually requires skilled operators to tune the machine, reducing the amount of available time for users.</description></item><item><title>Using Neural Network Control Policies For Rapid Switching Between Beam Parameters in a Free Electron Laser</title><link>https://RL4aa.github.io/posts/publications/edelen2017using2/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://RL4aa.github.io/posts/publications/edelen2017using2/</guid><description>A. L. Edelen1, S. G. Biedron2, J. P. Edelen3, S. V. Milton4, P. J. M. van der Slot5
1Colorado State University, 2Element Aero, 3Fermi National Accelerator Laboratory, 4Los Alamos National Laboratory, 5University of Twente
Workshop on Deep Learning for Physical Sciences at the Conference on Neural Information Processing Systems 2017
Abstract Free Electron Laser (FEL) facilities often must accommodate requests for a varietyof electron beam parameters in order to supply scientific users with appropriatephoton beam characteristics.</description></item></channel></rss>