<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>simulation only on RL4AA Collaboration | Homepage</title><link>https://RL4aa.github.io/tags/simulation-only/</link><description>Recent content in simulation only on RL4AA Collaboration | Homepage</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://RL4aa.github.io/tags/simulation-only/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Optimizing a superconducting radio-frequency gun using deep reinforcement learning</title><link>https://RL4aa.github.io/posts/publications/meier2022optimizing/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://RL4aa.github.io/posts/publications/meier2022optimizing/</guid><description>D. Meier1, L. V. Ramirez1, J. Völker1, J. Viefhaus1, B. Sick2, G. Hartmann1
1Helmholtz-Zentrum Berlin, 2University of Kassel
Physical Review Accelerators and Beams
Abstract Superconducting photoelectron injectors are promising for generating highly brilliant pulsed electron beams with high repetition rates and low emittances. Experiments such as ultrafast electron diffraction, experiments at the Terahertz scale, and energy recovery linac applications require such properties. However, optimizing the beam properties is challenging due to the high number of possible machine parameter combinations.</description></item><item><title>Orbit Correction Studies Using Neural Networks</title><link>https://RL4aa.github.io/posts/publications/meier2012orbit/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://RL4aa.github.io/posts/publications/meier2012orbit/</guid><description>E. Meier, Y.-R. E. Tan, G. S. LeBlanc
Australian Synchrotron
3rd International Particle Accelerator Conference
Abstract This paper reports the use of neural networks for orbitcorrection at the Australian Synchrotron Storage Ring. Theproposed system uses two neural networks in an actor-criticscheme to model a long term cost function and computeappropriate corrections. The system is entirely based onthe history of the beam position and the actuators, i.e. thecorrector magnets, in the storage ring.</description></item></channel></rss>