<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Announcements on RL4AA Collaboration | Homepage</title><link>https://RL4aa.github.io/categories/announcements/</link><description>Recent content in Announcements on RL4AA Collaboration | Homepage</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://RL4aa.github.io/categories/announcements/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>📍 RL4AA'24 call for abstracts extended to 5 January. Exciting keynote speakers announced. Register now!</title><link>https://RL4aa.github.io/posts/announcements/rl4aa24_last_chance/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://RL4aa.github.io/posts/announcements/rl4aa24_last_chance/</guid><description>The call for abstracts for the RL4AA'24 workshop, taking place 05 - 07 February 2024 in Salzburg, Austria, has been extended. Register for the workshop and submit your abstract until 5 January 2024!
We are also excited to announce our keynote speakers:
Antonin Raffin (German Aerospace Center) Felix Berkenkamp (Bosch Center for AI) For more information on the workshop, please see the official workshop website: https://rl4aa.github.io/RL4AA24/
To get directly to registration, please visit: https://indico.</description></item><item><title>Registration is now open for RL4AA'24 taking place 05 - 07 February 2024 in Salzburg, Austria</title><link>https://RL4aa.github.io/posts/announcements/rl4aa24_announcement/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://RL4aa.github.io/posts/announcements/rl4aa24_announcement/</guid><description>Announcing RL4AA'24 - Registration is open! Following up on the very successful RL4AA'23 workshop in Karlsruhe earlier this year, we are excited to announce the 2nd RL4AA workshop RL4AA'24, which will be held in Salzburg, Austria, from 05 - 07 February 2024. The workshop will be hosted at the Paris Lodron University of Salzburg. We are looking forward to an exciting workshop with many interesting talks and discussions on reinforcement learning for autonomous particle accelerators and hope to see you all in Salzburg!</description></item><item><title>The RL4AA Discord server is up!</title><link>https://RL4aa.github.io/posts/announcements/discord_server/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://RL4aa.github.io/posts/announcements/discord_server/</guid><description>Good News! The RL4AA community is happy to announce its Discord server! If you are interested in discussing reinforcement learning applied to accelerators, please join for announcements (e.g. new publications), forum discussions, an open chat, and meeting rooms.
Hope to see you there!
https://discord.gg/QtBMqsjWH2</description></item><item><title>The 2nd RL4AA workshop 2024 will be held 05 - 07 February 2024 in Salzburg</title><link>https://RL4aa.github.io/posts/announcements/rl4aa24_stay_tuned/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://RL4aa.github.io/posts/announcements/rl4aa24_stay_tuned/</guid><description>Good News - save the date! Our first workshop, RL4AA 2023, was very successful. Because of this, we are hoping to hold the 2nd RL4AA workshop in spring 2024 in Salzburg, Austria in 05 - 07 February 2024. Further details will follow soon.</description></item><item><title>RL4AA'23: 1st Collaboration Workshop on Reinforcement Learning for Autonomous Accelerators</title><link>https://RL4aa.github.io/posts/announcements/rl4aa23/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://RL4aa.github.io/posts/announcements/rl4aa23/</guid><description>Reinforcement learning is the most difficult learning paradigms to understand and to efficiently use, but it holds a lot of promise in the field of accelerator physics. The applications of reinforcement learning to accelerators today are not very numerous yet, but the interest of the community is growing considerably. This is how the 1st collaboration workshop on Reinforcement Learning for Autonomous Accelerators (RL4AA'23) came to be! The AI4Accelerators team organized and hosted the workshop at KIT, gathering colleagues involved in reinforcement learning.</description></item></channel></rss>